How can someone become financially free in today's world?
You know what I mean, rich.
It takes time.
What's up, guys?
Welcome back to another video
with the School of Hard Knocks.
I'm Jack here.
I'm here with James and Josh.
We are in downtown Austin.
Today, we're gonna be going around asking wealthy people
what is the best financial decision they've ever made.
Let's get to it.
What has been the best financial decision
that you've made throughout your career?
Invest in IT stocks early.
Was there a particular stock that you invested in?
Intel and Microsoft.
Those are the two biggies that
I had in the sale alone.
How long have you been in Microsoft for?
Oh my God, 20 plus.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
So I'm a cybersecurity executive.
If you were to go back to when
you were in either high school or college,
what is the best piece of
advice you'd tell your younger self?
Save your money.
Invest.
Don't spend more than you have.
Have a diverse portfolio.
401k, never touch it.
What has been the best
financial decision that you've ever made?
To walk away when someone
didn't actually value my contribution.
What impact did that have?
It had a huge impact because then
I went on to the next thing
and was shown that I was
right and the value was there.
When you're an entrepreneur and you're somebody
who runs large global businesses,
you are the value creation.
Make sure you understand that that's who you are
and that's what you're worth.
In what industry did you
decide to pursue a career in?
I'm the CEO of a technical legal services company.
I have employees all over the world.
We're headquartered here in Austin.
Being a woman in business and in a legal industry
that's highly technical is always challenging.
What's your best piece of advice
to someone trying to scale their business?
They take their business from
six to eight to ten figures
or whatever that may be.
Understand that you've got to have...
You've got to have leverage.
You've got to have the money to get there.
Understand cash flow is king.
You've got to have the ability
to deliver on your service line
and that's the only way you
sort of hit that next level.
You go beyond a plateau or
go beyond your next hockey stick.
What is your best piece of advice to
someone wanting to start a business in 2022?
No, you don't know everything.
Seek out advice.
Don't try to be everything for everybody.
You're going to need help.
Make sure you ask for it.
What is your best piece of advice to
someone wanting to start a business in 2022?
Have a unique idea.
Do something that hasn't been done.
And back yourself.
Go all in?
Yeah, or get the people
around you that believe in it.
Or get a partner.
What has been the best financial
decision that you made throughout your career?
It was working for myself.
I founded a company 20 something years ago and
sold it when I was 33, retired, and then
went back to work.
How much did you sell it for?
1 billion, 30 million.
Oh my gosh.
That's amazing.
It's true.
Wow.
What was the company?
It's called Webtrends Web Analytics.
Analyzing traffic to websites.
This is all pre-Google and so forth.
How can someone become successful?
financially free in today's world. Finding and
doing something that creates revenue for you when
you're not actually working, whether that's
investing, whether that's owning property and
renting it, whether that is, like I said, inventing
something or something that you sell. So as long
as you've got passive income, when you're
not physically doing whatever you're doing, you're
going to do very well in life. What do you
think people should be looking to put their money into
when they start making that money? Long-term real
estate has always been a consistent good play,
but technology stocks and the stock market is
still good. What is the best financial decision
that you've made in your career? I entered a
profession that gave me a lot of job security.
I never lived beyond my means. I was
fortunate to make some sensible investments. What advice
would you tell someone wanting to get into
investing? First of all, study it. Don't just
do what the herd is doing. These days, it
could be Robinhood, Reddit, and meme stocks. That is
just gambling, which is very different from
investing. Just go for the slow and steady.
Same with real estate.
You know, Austin's a fantastic example. Been
a very, very successful real estate market,
but it has bubble tendencies. So
if you actually wanted to invest locally,
you'd wait a year or two before you did
that. How could someone become financially free in 2022?
It's getting much harder. It's going to be much
harder for you guys than it was for me,
because you're competing globally and you're competing
with kids who are actually going to
sleep four hours a night. With that kind
of competition, you've really got to be at it.
The whole time. And what industry did
you decide to pursue a career in?
Madison. I think one of the craziest things about
Austin is that you really never know who you're
going to run into. You know, someone could
just be walking down the street, t-shirt flip-flops,
and that guy could be worth three, four,
five hundred million dollars. It's like the guy that
we interviewed, just walking around, t-shirt, shorts,
casually sold his company for a billion
dollars. You would have no idea. I think it's like
when you look at a city like Dallas, it's so bougie.
I think Dallas is a great city. It's very
kind of keeping up with the Joneses a little bit.
It's flashy. You know, if someone's got money, you're
going to be able to tell right away. Whereas
in Austin, you just see people walking on the street.
It's like, oh, I'm going to be able to tell
it. It's authentic, man. People are themselves. They
don't try and show it to other people.
Rather, they know that they've made it.
What has been the greatest financial decision that
you've made throughout your lifetime? I bought a
property over on Bee Caves 25 years ago that
became very valuable. How can someone become
financially free in today's world? You know what
I mean? Rich. It takes time. I became rich,
but it took time. That's an ingredient. What was the
biggest thing that led to your success and
that enabled you to acquire assets and build wealth?
I took chances. You don't accomplish anything if
you don't take risks. In what industry do
you decide to pursue a career? Pharmaceutical,
biotech, and commercial real estate. Wow. I was
a lucky guy. What advice would you tell
someone who's pursuing real estate? Learn from people
that know what the hell they're doing. Make
good connections, too, so that you become aware of
opportunities. The craziest thing that I've noticed
about the people that we do interview
is that the people who are typically most willing
to do interviews are people who are doing something
or they've gone through something in their life, I
feel like. Well, I've seen the majority of people
that are entrepreneurs are always 100 percent
down to do the interviews. It's because it's
almost like I feel like they were at a
point in time where they were trying to prove themselves,
and they know what it's like to hustle and have to
ask people like, hey, could I talk to you? Could I
network with you? Maybe we could collaborate on
something. They were there at that one point in
time. They didn't always have the money. They
didn't always have the big company. It's funny
when you see someone who's an entrepreneur, even before
you even find that out, you see their face
light up when you ask them to do the
interview. They're just like, yeah, let's do it. And then
you come to find out they own a business. It
makes total sense. Exactly. And you get some people who
give you some really rude rejections sometimes. I'm not even
going to lie. But I feel like even if an
entrepreneur doesn't have the time for it, maybe they're
on the way to the meeting, it's still good
energy. They respect the hustle. Dude, 100 percent.
It's like that Mark Cuban interview, man. It was
amazing that he said yes to us interviewing
him. He's got that young hustler mentality. He loves
young entrepreneurship. Exactly. It has no benefit
to him except helping out someone else. He's
supposed to see other people win. He's been at
a point where he had to prove himself before. Excuse
me, sir. I have a question for you. My brother,
my friend and I, we started a beauty team at UT
Austin. We created 1.1 million followers going all over
the country. I got it. He's got it too.
This goes to show not everyone wants to
do a video. That's why we always appreciate the
people that are willing to do so. But we'll
get the next one. What's the best financial decision
that you've made in your lifetime so far? Buying
a home, a multifamily home at a young age really
paid off for me. But again, I'd say
find a financial advisor and have a financial strategy
that fits you. There's no one size fits
all solution. What industry did you decide to pursue
a career in? I'm the assistant city manager for
the city of Austin. Oh, wow. That's amazing. Nice
to meet you. What's the best piece
of advice you tell your younger self?
Take more risks and worry less about the immediate
and what people are going to think about you
and what you say and what you do and
follow your heart. That wraps up today's video. Thank you
everyone for tuning in and for everyone
who's been showing love lately. We really appreciate
y'all. We've got a lot of great content coming
soon. If you enjoyed it, leave us a like,
subscribe. Keep tapping into the school
of hard knocks. Let's get it.